BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nahuel Brandán









ABOUT ME -

B.S in Computer Science / Backend Software Developer, specialized in Python, with over 3 years of experience in the industry, lately worked in the aerospace industry. Promoter of constant improvement in technical documentation and application of good development practices.

EXPERIENCE -

Company: Satellogic | Backend Developer

06/2022 - 09/2022

Company, vertically integrated, specialized in earth observation satellites.

- Development based on **Python**, applied to satellite flight applications.
- Refactoring of an application, to subdivide it into two others, thus reducing the coupling.
- Code reviews, and technical discussions, for the constant improvement of the source code.

Company: **Ascentio** | Project: **Sabia-Mar** | Backend Developer

08/2021 - 05/2022

Sabia-Mar is a satellite mission, with advanced technology for the study of the sea and the ocean.

- Contributions to different satellite flight planning and communication modules, using the technologies: Python, Docker, FastAPI, APIs.
- Developing both the software and the unit and integrator validation tests, using the technologies: Robot Framework, Postman, pytest.

Company: IncluIT | Project: Junar | Backend Developer

03/2019 - 07/2021

- Performing development activities in Python + Django + Django Rest Framework.
- Integration of **Autho** and **Keyclok** as a security layer to an **API Management**.
- Upgrade in Django versions and dependencies, thus reducing technical debt.
- Data handling and caching in different databases such as: Elasticsearch, Redis, Celery.
- Technical onboarding to new developers.

EDUCATION –

B.S in Computer Science - (completed) | Academy: FaMAF - UNC

10/2018

Career with strong emphasis on programming, analysis and design of systems, databases and computer networks, without neglecting the theoretical aspects that sustain them.

Self-study online courses | Academy: Platzi

01/2021 - Present

More than **100 courses completed** and in constant learning in the professional online academy called Platzi, on various topics such as: soft skills, English, software development.

SKILLS —

- Programming languages: Python, C.
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch.
- Frameworks: Django, Django REST Framework, FastAPI, Robot Framework.
- Others: Linux, REST API, Git, GitHub, Bash, Postman, Autho, Docker, Celery.

LANGUAGES

- English: **B1 intermediate**.
- Spanish: Native.

*